<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gardening on gardenR</title>
    <link>/categories/gardening/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gardening on gardenR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/gardening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Recap</title>
      <link>/post/2018-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-recap/</guid>
      <description>So I’m back - I have been altogether rubbish at keeping it updated in the summer. Too much fun was had between entering a new decade of my life, graduating (finally, I can use my Dr title and revive all those dying plants) and drinking lots of beer. There was also some gardening too.
I finally made some wins in the garden: I successfully grew cucamelons and chillies! I know I didn’t grow the chillies from seed, but I’m taking it as a massive win!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburg Parsley</title>
      <link>/post/hamburg-parsley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hamburg-parsley/</guid>
      <description>The plants in the greenhouse are growing now. It’s still quite chilly here, but I’m hoping it will heat up soon.
I’ve sown more seeds for the garlic chives because the ones I sowed a couple of weeks ago have not germinated. The old g. chives were from Poundworld and I’ve never been able to germinate them before. I’ve ordered a new batch from www.seekay.co.uk for 99p. I will update the status on their growth as time goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-week sowing</title>
      <link>/post/mid-week-sowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mid-week-sowing/</guid>
      <description>Sunshine at last! The UK has finally remembered it is spring! I celebrated by pressure washing the garden paths. Very rock and roll. I also did an inspection of the plants to see how they were getting on.
TreesBoth nectarine (varierty Harco) and the plum tree are in full flower. The plum tree is in its third spring now. I bought 5 dwarf fruit trees (2x apple - gala and golden delicious, 1 cherry - Stella, 1 plum - Stanley and 1 pear) in the first winter of moving here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to my first post! I am very pleased to have come this far. I have to admit, I’m not really sure I know what I’m doing with blogdown! Disclaimer alert if any links on the site don’t work, please leave me a comment and I’ll try to fix them.
Today I’m planning on deploying the site using Netlify because that’s what I’ve read on a couple of other blogs (https://alison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>