<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on gardenR</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on gardenR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic in the ground</title>
      <link>/post/garlic-in-the-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/garlic-in-the-ground/</guid>
      <description>Minimum temperatures are rising and seeds are germinating. This is the time of year I really look forward to; I can plan what I will grow, and then watch it slowly turn from my imagination into reality. Well, some sort of reality. Usually not quite how I’d planned. But still, exciting times are ahead.
AllotmentI spent this weekend planting up the garlic and onion sets that I’d started off in the greenhouse, at the allotment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye winter</title>
      <link>/post/goodbye-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/goodbye-winter/</guid>
      <description>Hello. It’s been quite frosty recently, so I’ve been sowing seeds inside and making a complete mess with perlite.
A few years ago, we had a terrible infestation with compost gnats when I reported a dragon tree, so I wanted to avoid that again this year. My bright idea was to buy loads of perlite and start the chillies and tomatoes off inside. I used this during my PhD very briefly and it was grand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday sowing</title>
      <link>/post/sunday-sowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sunday-sowing/</guid>
      <description>Allotment newsI’ve been up to the allotment this weekend and managed to clear away most of the remaining plants left by the previous owner. I now have a mostly cleared plot. Just some more weeding to do before it is totally clear, but I hoed all of the beds, so I’m hoping the frost will nip them dead so I don’t have to. There are some Calendula (AKA English marigold) there, which I intend to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allotment, Ahoy!</title>
      <link>/post/allotment-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/allotment-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>Allotment newsIt’s official: I am now renting an allotment! I went for a look on Saturday and was told a quarter plot was rough 8 x 8 m2. I also had a choice, which was nice. Plot was chosen: I was tempted to take the plot with lots of raspberry canes, but decided against it because there was more work than the other one.
Here are some pictures of the plot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New growing season</title>
      <link>/post/new-growing-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-growing-season/</guid>
      <description>PlansI’ve been beavering away at getting plants sorted and making plans for this year. I’ve already ordered some seed potatoes online (patchseedpotatoes.co.uk), from the motherland (N. Ireland). I’m quite excited because they are unusual varieties: - purple rain: second early. It has purple skin and flesh. I tried similar from Lidl last year and they were delicious and weird looking on the plate.
Purple Rain: image from https://www.patchseedpotatoes.co.uk/product/purple-rain-seed-potatoes/
Highland Burgundy red: this potato has red flesh, hailing from Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Recap</title>
      <link>/post/2018-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-recap/</guid>
      <description>So I’m back - I have been altogether rubbish at keeping it updated in the summer. Too much fun was had between entering a new decade of my life, graduating (finally, I can use my Dr title and revive all those dying plants) and drinking lots of beer. There was also some gardening too.
I finally made some wins in the garden: I successfully grew cucamelons and chillies! I know I didn’t grow the chillies from seed, but I’m taking it as a massive win!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chive pesto recipe</title>
      <link>/post/chive-pesto-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chive-pesto-recipe/</guid>
      <description>In my last blog post, I promised a recipe for chive pesto. I stumbled across the recipe when I was searching for what to do with a large amount of chives; most of the suggestions were “sprinkle on soups” or “use in an omelette”. There’s only so many omelettes and soups a person can have before they go off. Plus, I wanted to make chives the main feature – not have it as something thrown in at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: summer has kicked in!</title>
      <link>/post/update-summer-has-kicked-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/update-summer-has-kicked-in/</guid>
      <description>I’m back! It’s been a while since I’ve had time to blog. I’ve been very busy with the garden - and we also went on holiday to Vietnam where mangos, jack fruit, kumquats and pomegranate are grown there with relative ease. It puts my garden to shame!
Summer has finally started! It hasn’t rained very much in the last two months, so I have been very busy watering the garden. The beds remain very dry and we have had a few casualties along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers galore</title>
      <link>/post/flowers-galore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/flowers-galore/</guid>
      <description>Hi again - quick update on things so far. The weather is still very warm and sunny, so everything is finally catching up with the cold start to spring. That said, it has only rained twice in almost four weeks. Things are very dry!
I had to get the hose out and water the raised beds because I noticed that the flowers from the broadbeans were just dropping off and no pods were setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring is here!</title>
      <link>/post/spring-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spring-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Google AnalyticsI’ve been working on trying to integrate Google Analytics into this blog, so I can see how many people are actually reading it. Easy, right? HA! It should have worked fine, but as with everything, I had a bit of a nightmare. So the workflow is basically: set up a GA account, paste in the tracking code into your blogdown config.toml file (if your theme has this feature built in - and the one I’m using does) and it should work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesky pests</title>
      <link>/post/pesky-pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pesky-pests/</guid>
      <description>Hello from sunny Leeds! Yes, more sunshine has been sent. Today has been really warm and the bank holiday weather was good for the plants.
Note: I compress the images for the web, but I’ve noticed the quality is pretty naff and they go all blurred. Will look into improving these in the future.
To begin, I will start with the ongoing experiment. The conclusion is: chili seeds do not like to germinate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburg Parsley</title>
      <link>/post/hamburg-parsley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hamburg-parsley/</guid>
      <description>The plants in the greenhouse are growing now. It’s still quite chilly here, but I’m hoping it will heat up soon.
I’ve sown more seeds for the garlic chives because the ones I sowed a couple of weeks ago have not germinated. The old g. chives were from Poundworld and I’ve never been able to germinate them before. I’ve ordered a new batch from www.seekay.co.uk for 99p. I will update the status on their growth as time goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocktail Kiwis</title>
      <link>/post/cocktail-kiwis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cocktail-kiwis/</guid>
      <description>Today I purchased two small plants (around 9cm of so) of the Kiwi variety Issai. I also bought this a couple of years ago in a 2 litre pot from Suttons, but I spied these plants in Morrisons for £2 each and couldn’t resist - some even have flower buds, but it is good practice to pick these out and leave them to focus their energy on growth. I bought a lemon balm plant pot, which I’m going to separate out and put in my herb patch and in some pots around the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-week sowing</title>
      <link>/post/mid-week-sowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mid-week-sowing/</guid>
      <description>Sunshine at last! The UK has finally remembered it is spring! I celebrated by pressure washing the garden paths. Very rock and roll. I also did an inspection of the plants to see how they were getting on.
TreesBoth nectarine (varierty Harco) and the plum tree are in full flower. The plum tree is in its third spring now. I bought 5 dwarf fruit trees (2x apple - gala and golden delicious, 1 cherry - Stella, 1 plum - Stanley and 1 pear) in the first winter of moving here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHT22 success!</title>
      <link>/post/dht22-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dht22-success/</guid>
      <description>More Pi funSo after yesterday’s massive fail, I decided to go with (https://www.hackster.io/adamgarbo/raspberry-pi-2-iot-thingspeak-dht22-sensor-b208f4). It took me around 5 minutes to set up. Boo! I wanted to use the other one because I was interested in the MySQL side of things. Therefore, this is a temporary measure and I will do my own programming to get it working. I’ve been working on a similar project in work to collect data, store it in a DB and write it to the php script so I will have to rememeber how to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi fun</title>
      <link>/post/raspberry-pi-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/raspberry-pi-fun/</guid>
      <description>Today I tried to set up my Pi and the DHT22 sensor. It was all going to well in the beginning. The stuff I ordered from eBay arrived really fast (see references section for supplier details) and I was bright eyed and bushy tailed this morning at 10am.
Problem number 1: I have no idea about electronicsTo elaborate, I tried to use a couple of really great tutorials I found online, to help set up the sensor and store the data in a mysql database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to my first post! I am very pleased to have come this far. I have to admit, I’m not really sure I know what I’m doing with blogdown! Disclaimer alert if any links on the site don’t work, please leave me a comment and I’ll try to fix them.
Today I’m planning on deploying the site using Netlify because that’s what I’ve read on a couple of other blogs (https://alison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>